<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MindNest</string>
    <string name="Equal_Breathing">
How to Practice:\n
1. Sit comfortably with a straight spine or lie down.\n\n
2. Inhale deeply through the nose for a count of 4.\n\n
3. Exhale smoothly through the nose for the same count of 4.\n\n
4. Gradually increase the count (e.g., 5-6 seconds) as you become more comfortable.\n\n

\nBenefits:\n
1. Reduces stress and anxiety by activating the parasympathetic nervous system.\n\n
2. Improves focus and mental clarity.\n\n
3. Balances energy and promotes relaxation.\n\n
4. Enhances lung capacity and respiratory efficiency.\n\n

\nBest For:\n
Beginners, as it’s simple yet powerful. It can be practiced anytime—before sleep, during work breaks, or to start meditation.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="Box_Breathing">
How to Practice:\n
1. Sit upright in a comfortable position, keeping your spine straight.\n\n
2. Inhale deeply through your nose for a count of 4.\n\n
3. Hold your breath for a count of 4.\n\n
4. Exhale slowly through your nose for a count of 4.\n\n
5. Hold your breath again for a count of 4 before repeating.\n\n
6. Continue this cycle for 3-5 minutes, maintaining even counts.\n\n

\nBenefits:\n
1. Calms the nervous system, reducing stress and anxiety.\n\n
2. Enhances focus and mental clarity by regulating breath control.\n\n
3. Improves emotional regulation and resilience.\n\n
4. Boosts oxygenation and lung efficiency.\n\n
5. Used by athletes, military personnel, and professionals for peak performance.\n\n

\nBest For:\n
Those seeking deep relaxation, improved concentration, or stress relief. Ideal before high-pressure situations, meditation, or bedtime. Also beneficial for beginners due to its structured, easy-to-follow pattern.
</string>


    <string name="four_seven_eight_Breathing">
How to Practice:\n
1. Sit or lie down in a comfortable position, placing the tip of your tongue against the ridge behind your upper front teeth.\n\n
2. Exhale completely through your mouth, making a "whoosh" sound.\n\n
3. Close your mouth and inhale quietly through your nose for a count of 4.\n\n
4. Hold your breath for a count of 7.\n\n
5. Exhale fully through your mouth (with the "whoosh" sound) for a count of 8.\n\n
6. Repeat this cycle 3-4 times initially, gradually working up to 8 cycles.\n\n

\nBenefits:\n
1. Rapidly reduces stress and anxiety by activating the parasympathetic nervous system.\n\n
2. Promotes better sleep and relaxation when practiced before bedtime.\n\n
3. Helps control cravings and emotional responses.\n\n
4. Improves focus and mindfulness by regulating breath patterns.\n\n
5. May lower blood pressure and ease tension.\n\n

\nBest For:\n
Those dealing with insomnia, anxiety, or acute stress. Also useful for quick relaxation during the day. Not recommended for beginners to do excessively—start with fewer cycles to avoid lightheadedness.
    </string>
</resources>